### Contact

saraiva.ufc@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saraivaufc (LinkedIn)

www.saraiva.dev (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Python

**Data Science** 

Artificial Intelligence (AI)

## Languages

Português (Native or Bilingual)

English (Professional Working)

#### Certifications

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC)

Verified International Academic Qualifications

DevOps Essentials Professional Certificate (DEPC)

### **Publications**

Automatic Mapping of Center Pivot Irrigation Systems from Satellite Images Using Deep Learning

Construção de Mosaicos Temporais Normalizados de Imagens Planet

Reconstructing Three Decades of Land Use and Land Cover Changes in Brazilian Biomes with Landsat Archive and Earth Engine

# Marciano Saraiva

Solutions Consultant | Data Science | Big Data | Machine Learning | Geoprocessing | Remote Sensing

Florianópolis, Santa Catarina, Brazil

# Summary

As a Solutions Consultant at Brain Agriculture, I apply my geotechnology expertise to innovate in remote sensing for agriculture. With 7 years in the field, I'm skilled in Python and AI tools, focusing on land use mapping and satellite imagery. I have an Information Systems degree from UFC and two postgraduates in AI and Data Science from PUC Minas. Certified in Scrum and DevOps, I excel in agile, quality solutions. Visit my portfolio at www.saraiva.dev to see my work. Let's connect to share ideas on tech's evolving role.

# Experience

**Brain Agriculture** 

2 years 6 months

**Solutions Consultant** 

July 2022 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Indaiatuba, São Paulo, Brazil

- Land use and land cover mapping using machine learning tools;
- Processing of satellite images;
- Development of geographic information systems;
- Leads the development of Remote sensing products.

### Senior Software Development Analyst

October 2021 - June 2022 (9 months)

Indaiatuba, São Paulo, Brazil

- Land use and land cover mapping using machine learning tools;
- Processing of satellite images;
- Development of geographic information systems.

Agrosatellite Applied Geotechnology

4 years 2 months

Senior Software Development Analyst

October 2019 - September 2021 (2 years)

Florianópolis e Região, Brasil

- Development of geographic information systems
- Land Use and Land Cover Mapping using Machine Learning
- Satellite image processing
- Analysis and exploration of geospatial data

Mid-level Software Development Analyst May 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 5 months)

Florianópolis, Santa Catarina, Brazil

Trainee Software Development Analyst August 2017 - April 2018 (9 months) Florianópolis, Santa Catarina, Brazil

Freelance (Self employed)
Freelance
January 2017 - July 2017 (7 months)
Brazil

Federal University of Ceará Software Development Intern January 2016 - December 2016 (1 year) Quixadá e Região, Brasil

## Education

Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais
Postgraduate (Lato Sensu), Artificial Intelligence and Machine
Learning · (2020 - 2021)

Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais

Postgraduate (Lato Sensu), Data Science and Big Data · (2019 - 2020)

Federal University of Ceará
Bachelor degree, Information Systems · (2013 - 2016)